kapilarya.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

We here at **Kapil Sparks™** respect your privacy. Your privacy is of paramount importance to us and we are always committed to safeguarding it. This _Privacy Policy_ explains what happens to any personal data that you provide to us, or that we collect from you whilst you visit our site. We do update this policy from time to time so please do review it regularly.

**KapilArya.Com** does not collect any personal information about you such as your name, address, phone number or e-mail ID without your knowledge. When you provide your e-mail ID while contacting us using [contact page](https://www.kapilarya.com/contact), we never share it with anyone. We only use it to respond to your e-mail.

When you submit a comment, the e-mail ID you provide is stored in our database which helps the website to recognize you when you comment next time. If your previous comment was approved, then site recognizes you at new comment automatically and approves the newer comment without moderation. We don’t share your e-mail ID to anyone.

#### About cookies

A possible interaction between a web browser and a server holding a web page in which the server sends a cookie to the browser and the browser sends it back when requesting another page. Cookies are arbitrary pieces of data, usually chosen by the web server, and stored on the client computer by the browser.

Cookies can be used by web servers to identity and track users as they navigate different pages on a website and to identify users returning to a website.

Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies. A persistent cookie consists of a text file sent by a web server to a web browser, which will be stored by the browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date (unless deleted by the user before the expiry date). A session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.

This website uses both type of cookies. Cookies helps us to store a bit of website data on your device, which helps your browsing experience for this site, in successive sessions.

We use _Google Analytics_ to analyse the use of this website. _Google Analytics_ generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users’ computers. The information generated relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of the website. _Google_ will store this information. _Google_ ‘s privacy policy is available [here](https://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

When you use this website, you may also be sent third-party cookies.

Our advertisers i.e. _Google Adsense_ may send you cookies. They may use the information they obtain from your use of their cookies:

  * To track your browser across multiple websites.

  * To build a profile of your web surfing.

  * To target advertisements which may be of particular interest to you.

Our advertising services providers may send you cookies for the purpose of enabling the service of advertisements based on your previous visits to our website.

We publish _Google Adsense_ interest-based advertisements on our website. These are tailored by _Google_ to reflect your interests. To determine your interests, _Google_ will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the web using the _DART_ cookie. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser using _Google’s Ads Preference Manager_ , available at **[here](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/)**. You can opt-out of the _Adsense partner network cookie_ on that same page. To ensure that an opt-out is maintained in respect of a particular browser, you should use the _Google browser plug-in_ available at **[Google Ad preferences](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/plugin)**. You may also opt-out advertising cookies by clearing them under your browser settings.

Browsing this website and using the information shared here clearly implies that you’re accepting the above mentioned policies. Please feel free to **[contact us](https://www.kapilarya.com/contact)** for any questions or concerns regarding your privacy.

Last updated : July 29, 2015.

_Thanks for your support!_
